# Nikhil Sharma



nikhil191995@gmail.com



+91 98680 73067



linkedin.com/in/nikhil-sharma-9300b0125

# **Summary**

Python Developer with 4+ years of experience working in Big Data along with Scala and Spark. Developed server side logic and wrote ETL pipelines for loading and transforming data. I have worked in healthcare, sports, media and retail domain. Currently working in insurance domain where I write ETL pipelines for a medical source.

Hands on experience working with AWS(EC2, ASG, Load Balancers, WAF) and Azure(Databricks, Notebooks, Blob)

# **Experience**



## **Senior Software Engineer**

GlobalLogic

Sep 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

**FocusVision** 

- Developing server-side logic for a survey creation tool in Python and Django.
- Deploying application on AWS cloud using awsebcli for deployments on EB managed services.
- Syncing and upload of media and static files to Amazon S3 bucket using Python boto or directly attaching roles to the EC2 instances for AWS cli tool.
- · Configured auto scaling groups and application load balancers for high availability of the application.
- Building functionality for bulk uploading receipts emails for email marketing campaigns.
- Fixed a tool for a format named ".sav" which used to show "Date" types as "String" types. This format is used with IBM tool known as SPSS which is used for statistical analysis.

#### Health Insurance Project

- Writing ETL pipelines for medical insurance files and transforming the data as per requirements using Scala and Spark.
- Wrote configuration files for building single jar for multi module maven project so that all the source system jobs can be run at once using same jar file.
- Developed logic for scraping ICD codes files from cms website and parsing it to use it for further transformation in ETL pipeline.

# Associate Software Engineer

ReTech Labs, Inc.

Aug 2018 - Sep 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Worked on a retail SaaS platform where large retail stores use this service to remodel their stores or reshelving by providing skilled workers cost efficiently. The platform is built upon Python, Django, DRF, Angular1, PostgreSQL.

#### SAS Retail

- Upgraded the server-side logic for SAS retail from Python 2 and Django 1.7 to Python 3 and Django 1.11.
- Parsed large datasets for warehousing using Python and Spark(PySpark).

- · Deploying code to AWS EBS using aws cli.
- Developed PTO module for the workers that were deployed to stores using the software to stores.
- Optimized ORM queries for better response time.

# Backend Developer

Innotical Solutions - Web and App Development Company | 100% Delivery Record Jul 2016 - Aug 2018 (2 years 2 months)

Worked on multiple projects in different domains and writing server side logic catering to the requirements specified by clients and client-side. Deploying projects on AWS

#### **Email Verification**

- Writing server-side logic for an eyeglass company to parse files in the format of csv using Python and Spark and then showing it on the front-end using API's.
- Use of telnet and smtp to verify if emails are existent or not.

#### MySwaasth

- Writing server-side logic in Python and Django which lists nearby hospitals and their doctors in the area.
- Wrote the functionality of searching doctors, medications and hospitals using elasticsearch and Python without using solr and haystack.
- Used geopy to list hospitals in the nearby area based on the location of users.
- Developed a different entity for hospitals and clinics for taking appointments from patients.

#### Pelotea

- Pelotea is an amateur soccer league based in Ecuador.
- Rewriting the server-side logic in Python3 and Django 1.11 from Python2 and Django 1.7.
- Optimisation of ORM gueries for better performance.
- Handling tech team responsible for developing the product.

#### GoPlayBook

- GoPlayBook is an sports app where users can score their cricket and football matches and book venue for the same developed in Python and Django.
- Developed logic for taking bookings and search of users, venues and top leagues.

### **Education**



### **Chaudhary Charan Singh University**

BCA, Computer Science 2013 - 2016



## **Guru Harkrishan Public School**

12, Science 2011 - 2013



### **Guru Harkishan Public School**

High School Diploma, Computer Science 2009 - 2011

# **Skills**

Python (Programming Language) • Django • DRF • GIT • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • JIRA • Azure Databricks • Apache Spark

# **Honors & Awards**



Spot Award - GlobalLogic

Sep 2020

Spot Award for excellent performance